It's time to texture these bad boys.
Finally, after hinting at it for so
long.
Um so, we added some simple materials
and uh that is actually fine for some
types of objects. Like, you might
actually have a plate and go like, it's
just white plate. Doesn't need any
texture. But, most things need texture.
So, I'm going to select my uh table
floor here. I'm going to go to the
material panel right here. And I'm going
to add a new material since it doesn't
have one. And um let's look at how to
add a texture. So, right here where
we've got base color, if we want to add
a color texture, we just click on this
little uh yellow dot next to it. I know
that's not clear. It will become clear
when I show you nodes. Um but, when I
click this, you get this uh slide-out
menu with a bunch of different options
here. Um and the one that I'm looking
for says image texture. Okay. So, now I
can hit um open.
And just to demonstrate this, I'm going
to select a wood texture that I
downloaded off the internet just to show
you how this works. Now, on this note,
if you happen to see this, if you use an
image texture that you find online, it's
because there is a new feature feature.
Uh
it that there's a purpose. There's a
There's a new feature in Blender 5.0
where if it identifies in the name
anything from the number 1,000 to 2,000,
I think, um it'll think that is a UDIM,
which is a completely whole, you know,
production professional workflow kind of
thing.
Um it'll think it's a UDIM. And it
Anyways, what you need to do is then
change this to single image. But, most
of the time, most images, if it doesn't
have those numbers uh a string at the
end, it should just load in fine.
Anyways, let's say you had an image like
this. Um you wanted the table to look uh
wood, right? We're not going to do that,
but you know, just just to show you.
Um
you would see it it's okay, right? But,
there is no bump information. Okay? Um
and that is because, of course, the 3D
software doesn't know that there's
supposed to be crevices here, right?
Little dips in between the table, the
the fine tooth uh grain of it. It has no
idea because it's just taken with a
single camera. It would have no idea how
to guest guest what that true
information should be. I mean, there is
technically a way to guess it, but it
never really turns out well. Um so, I'm
not even going to bother showing you. Um
so, most of the time, when you're
talking about texturing in 3D um and
using image textures, like textures from
the real world, um you don't just grab a
random image texture that you find
online. You need to use a PBR textures,
which stands for physically based
rendering textures. And there are many
different places that you can get PBR
textures from. The best website that I
think is Polygon, p o l i i g o n dot
com. The link is below.
Um and I think it's the best website
because it's my website. It's my
company.
Um which I created 10 years ago, and it
is now the fastest growing texture
library
um online. Um so, we've got
photographers all over the world, and
they use specialized equipment to go out
into the world and they capture surfaces
um usually like photograph the surface
like hundreds of times, which is what
enables you to actually capture all of
that height information, the bump, uh
the shininess reflectiveness of
materials.
Um and actually capture all of the maps
that you can see here, for example.
These weird-looking maps um is exactly
what Blender um needs to
uh to to make the material look
realistic. So, we've got a bunch of
different categories, obviously like
almost anything you want to create, um
you can find the textures um on here.
But, for just this tutorial, if you go
to polygon.com/a
donut, the link for that is also below.
Um but, this has the uh six textures
that you'll actually need to follow
along for this video.
Um they're all free. We've made them
free. All you need to do is get a free
account, um and you can download all of
those by just clicking them and then
hitting uh download. And also, if you
scroll down, uh we've got some premium
textures here if you have uh a
subscription with us um that you could
use for the cafe scene that we're making
to kind of spruce it up, make it your
own, add some variation there. Um so,
we've included some ones here that go
well uh with the scene. Um and if you
use this link, you'll get 10% off uh any
any uh plan you choose. So, the first
texture I want you to start with is uh
it's going to be our cafe table. Um and
obviously, you could, you know, you
could use any texture that. You could
use, you know, some of the ones down
there if you wanted to. Um but, I want
you to start with this one, this
concrete texture. Um because we're going
to make this look like a concrete table,
something that, you know, a lot of cafes
can sometimes have. Now, we actually
have a Blender add-on, which makes
downloading and importing these things
even simpler. But, I want to give you
the traditional way to import PBR
textures first, so that you know how to
use PBR textures just flat. Um and then
I want to show you the easy way after.
So, once you've got your free account,
you can come back here, and you can
click on download, this big download
button. So, that'll give you an 8K uh
texture. You probably don't need it. You
could probably get by with four, but I'm
going to get the 8K just to show you how
it looks. Now, this will download a zip
file like here. Okay? So, it should be
fairly quick. It's about 289 megs. Once
you've downloaded this texture, I need
you to unzip it. So, with Windows, you
just right-click and go uh extract all.
Uh if you're on a Mac, you just
double-click it, and it should just
unzip itself. Now that I've got that,
you can
It's the stuff that's in here. This is
the good stuff. This is the one we
actually need to use. So, I'm going to
uh just copy this folder uh location,
and then uh back in Blender, for my
selected plane here, underneath base
color, I'm just going to uh just like
before, you know, select image texture
if you haven't already. Then, I'm going
to click open. And then, a lot of these
images look pretty similar. There's very
little detail across them. There is
some, uh but the one we're looking for
is _base color. So, that is the one
we're going to start with. Okay. So,
this has given us a nice clean de-lit
concrete floor texture, but the same
problem. We don't have that height
information there. And that's because,
just like before, we've only loaded in
information into the base color. So,
it's it's almost like this has been
printed on cardboard. That's kind of the
appearance there. So, we need to load in
the other PBR texture uh maps, they're
called uh all of those uh different uh
images that we downloaded. And we could,
you know, import and do them the same
way by clicking these little dot and
then go image texture. But, it's very
fiddly. And this view here, you can
probably tell is like it's not designed
for like complex texturing work. If you
want to do complex texturing work, you
should click on the shading tab at the
top of your screen. Now, this view looks
completely different. You've got a 3D
view at the top. You've got these nodes
here, which are very useful. And then,
you got two over here that I think are
kind of pointless. I don't really think
they should be here.
Um I've never really wanted them. So,
I'm going to right-click on the uh
like the divider between these little
windows here. I'm going to say join
left. And then, I'm going to do the same
for the bottom, join left. And then, I
also I want to flip it because I haven't
I don't really like having like the top
view and this. It's like it's too
wide-screen to like look at things like
this. So, instead, I'm going to
right-click this, say join uh down. And
then, at the top of my screen here, the
top of the little uh divider there,
until I get that little uh little
arrows, I'm going to right-click, and
then I'm going to say vertical split.
And then, to make this one on the
right-hand side, those same shader nodes
that we had from before, click from this
little drop-down at the top. Uh by the
way, if you don't see it, um you just
have to like middle mouse like grab and
pull across, and you will get uh all the
way to the end there.
Uh but yeah, if I click that and then go
shader editor,
then close this by hitting the N key.
It's a lot of steps. Uh but now, I have
my shader nodes. So, the shader nodes
over here, this is actually the same
information as what we have in our
material over here. For example, if I
was to uh adjust this roughness, you can
see that it's adjusting both of those
values there. And when we added in this,
and we we clicked image texture, it was
basically in the background adding in
this node here, which loaded in the
image texture. So, this is a it's a
simplified view. If you want to do like
small changes to a material, you use
this panel here. If you want to do
anything more complex than that, you use
the shader nodes here. And it's pretty
self-explanatory to understand how
shader nodes work. It's like over here,
this is your material output. It's the
final material. And generally, you have
a shader, which is something like this,
principled BSDF, that is the shader that
you use for like 99% of materials now.
And then, you just have a bunch of
values. And then, you can connect things
into this um to do different things. And
I'm going to show you how we can like
tweak this texture and do a bunch of
stuff. Um but, first, let's load in some
of those PBR texture maps. By the way,
if you're wondering uh the one the view
on the left-hand side of the screen
here, why does this look different? This
is because, and again, a middle mouse
drag along the top there, um
we we talked about the 3D viewport. We
talked about the rendered view mode. We
didn't talk about this one. This is the
material preview mode. And it's
literally designed for previewing
materials because it loads in a like
fake world view around a called an HDR,
which you can actually swap out here, so
you can see, you know, different types
of uh environments. But, it's a way to
like quickly visualize a material
um without having to like change a bunch
of lighting to understand how the
material's going to look cuz materials
look very different in different uh
lighting setups. So, it's actually a
very useful mode, um and it makes sense.
It's called material preview. So, let's
load in another image. So, I'm going to
hit uh uh I could hit shift A, or I
could just go add at the top of the
screen there. It's cool. The Blender's
hot keys are the exact same ones
everywhere. So, shift A is the same as
shift A over there, right? Add.
And I'm going to go texture and I'm
going to say image texture. Okay. And
now it's just asking where do you want
to drop it, so I can just drop it
anywhere. And I'm going to click open.
Then I'm going to navigate to that
folder where all of the images are. And
the first one I'm going to load in is
this one called underscore normal, the
purple one.
And it's you can remember it as the
normal map because it's normal to ask
why is that purple? That's how I
remember it.
>> [laughter]
>> Then yeah, just hit open on that.
And the place that you would put that,
you could guess, is the normal input,
that little purple input there on our
shader there. So, the way you connect
something to something else is you just
where there's a point, you just click
that point and you just drag out and
connect it to another point and then you
release. And then it is connected.
Now, you can see that there is some bump
information now. But you wouldn't know
it, but this is actually the wrong
What's It's partly the way to connect
something, but we need to do something
else. First of all, you can see that
between here and here Whoops.
We've gone from a yellow input to a
purple input. Now, it's okay to go from
like yellow to gray because gray just
means gray scale, so you can go from
color information to gray information,
that's fine. But normal is like vector
information. Yeah, without getting
technical, like the normal is the way
the faces, like that invisible line of
the faces, and this is like faking which
direction each of those pixels has.
Um
But basically, we need to add something
between here and here to convert this
from color information into vector
information. And we can do that by
hitting shift A to add again, and then
going to displacement in this drop-down
and clicking normal map. You can also,
if you can't find it, you can go to the
search bar and you can type in normal
map as well. All right, once you've got
this normal map, you then just need to
drag it over that line until it lights
up, and then you just want to do a
single click and it will connect it.
Okay. So, now it is correctly connected.
But it But still, it's just not quite
right. There are There is a lot of steps
to like manually connecting PBR texture
maps, which is why I want to show you
the fast way to do this after this. But
I need to show you this because you
might be using PBR texture maps from
elsewhere or from like production files
and stuff, and you need to know how to
actually manually connect them. So, when
you're working with PBR texture maps,
the only texture that should have the
color space sRGB is your base color,
okay?
Every other map should have the color
space set to non-color. And again,
without going technical I keep saying
that because you shaders are very
technical.
It It basically it's it's it's
converting it to linear space. So, it's
using that
Or it's actually not doing any
conversion. It's just saying like let's
use the raw values from that and
just use it linear. I don't Yeah,
anyway.
>> [laughter]
>> Other Other software sometimes call
those maps, but our Blender's is a
non-color data. Okay. So, now that we've
got that, look, we've got bump across
our concrete there. And if we went into
the rendered view at the top there,
you could see if I took my lamp at the
top there, and then I brought this like
way down to the
plane that you can see we get this like
nice gritty shadows cast across the
surface there.
Um
And this is how you make materials that
look realistic. You can't get this
information any other way than by
very expensively capturing these
surfaces, and I know that because I've
seen the bills. I know how much it costs
to capture surfaces like this.
And it can be thousands. That's where we
started, and over the years we've got
that price way way down.
But it's it's a very expensive capturing
process. It's not easy to do. It's not
fun. It's very boring to do. So, unless
you really want to go into that space,
it's not something you want to try to
do.
Anyways, so that's the normal map, but
there is another map which is useful.
So, I'm going to hit shift A to add
another map, and I'm going to say
texture, and I'm looking for image
texture. Okay. And then I'm going to
click open on this, and this time I'm
looking for the one with underscore
roughness at the end of the name.
Okay. And then just like before, I need
to make sure my color space is set to
non-color data. And then finally, I want
to drag this out to plug into my
roughness input.
Now, when you do that, you'll see the
material goes very very dull. So, it was
like, you know, before when we set this
to like shiny like this,
when we connect this in here it goes
dull because concrete is dull. So, this
is actually like the correct value for
concrete. We like calibrated it to make
sure. So, this is is that. Now, it's
very often that you actually want to
customize something. Like, for example,
cafe tables often have concrete that has
been like buffed or like coated in some
sort of gloss or something like that or
an epoxy. So, it can It It's totally
fine to just want to have like the free
control of the slider there and not use
it. Like, the maps are there if you need
them, right? If you really want to go
for something realistic, you would use
them all, but sometimes you don't, and
it's totally fine to just disconnect
them. Now, the other maps here, by the
way, if you're curious, this yellow one,
ORM, we don't use that in Blender,
that's used by game engines. Polygon
provides them because we, you know,
serve all the different renderers and
softwares out there. Displacement is a
different method than normal map. We're
actually going to use that on the donut.
Metallic is if the material contains
metal, that's the only time you would
use that. And then the other one is
occlusion map, an ambient occlusion map.
That's if it there's like deep crevices,
like if it's like a pebble pathway or
something like that. This is the actual
like shadows that like collects inside
of crevices.
But we don't need that. Honestly, most
of the time these three maps, the base
color, the normal map, and the
roughness, that is like 90% materials.
And that's really all that you need for
those. But it is still very finicky to
do this, right? Am I wrong? Like, having
to remember the color space and connect
this and convert that and like even just
these three things was like 30 clicks.
So, that is why most people that are
dealing with PBR textures don't want to
have to do this. They want to use an
add-on like
the Polygon add-on. So, at the top of
the page on polygon.com \slash} donut,
you can click this link that says
download Polygon add-on, or you can just
go to \slash} Blender. This will show
you how to install it. If you don't want
to read that, I'll show you how to do it
right now. Unlike before, when you have
your zip file, do not unzip it. Blender
actually needs this zip in order to
properly install it. So, what you do is
you drag out and you release the zip
file from anywhere on the computer, and
then it will say install this because
it'll recognize it as an add-on, and
then you say yep, install, and you say
okay. Now, if you go to edit
preferences, then go to add-ons, you
should see one there called Polygon at
the top there, which means it has been
successfully installed. If it didn't
successfully install, maybe you're on a
Mac and maybe it actually automatically
unzipped itself, in which case you need
to rezip it and then drag it over. But
yeah, it should install if it is
properly zipped. Now, once you have done
that, in your 3D viewport over here, if
you hit N, which brings up your
properties, you should see a tab there
that says Polygon. Then if you just like
one-click login, this will take you here
and then it will just say login
confirmed. Go back into Blender and you
should see now we've got materials in a
scroll bar, right? Which is pretty cool,
and I can type in anything I want. Let's
say
sprinkles cuz I know there's some
sprinkles materials here, for example.
But you can also browse by category,
right? You can look at all the different
ones. And importantly, this will
actually download it. So, one-click
download like this, and then one-click
apply, and look at this.
All of this has been set up
automatically. All of these are
automatically set to non-color. We've
got the exact precise
correct use of every single map that is
ready to go.
But anyway, go back to my previous
material here, and let's go to
free category, and then let's use
another one. So, this speckled glazed
ceramic plate.
And by the way, you can like click the
little drop-down there if you want to
see something online to get like better
picture for it,
you can quickly view it that way. But
this is the one we want to apply to our
plate here. So, with my plate selected,
I need to first of all hit download.
I've already done it, which is why I
don't see it, but you hit download and
it'll just save it to your folder, which
is in your preferences. And then with an
object selected, you should be able to
hit apply. If you don't see the apply
box, it means that you haven't got an
object selected, so make sure one is
selected in order to click that box.
Okay. So, we have correctly
applied it. You can see all the nodes
are there. It's the correct material.
Why isn't it showing up on our object?
Now, this isn't a fault of the texture
or anything like that. This is to do
with texture mapping, which is the next
thing to understand when it comes to
textures. Is textures are 2D, right? 2D.
And our objects are obviously 3D. So,
how do you apply a texture to an object?
There are so many different ways. And
the most common way is to use UV
unwrapping, which is the default method,
which is what it's actually looking for
right now. You can see that's the
texture coordinate that it's called in
is UVs. And for something like a plate,
this is the most simplest thing ever cuz
it's just creating UVs. So, in edit
mode, so just tab, and then select your
entire mesh like that. Then hit U, U for
unwrap, and then select unwrap angle
based. And look, now the texture has
been applied. So, what did that actually
do? If you go to your UV editing tab at
the top of your screen there, just click
that, you will see, and let's uh focus
on our object, so number pad right
there, and I'll just uh turn this off so
we can see the mesh underneath it, and
this one as well. And let's look at uh
the wireframe. Okay, so when we UV
unwrapped it, it basically took I mean,
it in in the case of something as flat
as this, it just took a snapshot of it,
and then it put it into the 2D space
over here. And from your drop down, you
could actually change it to the color
map, and you could see where it's
actually applied to on it. So, if I
select a point right here on the mesh,
you can see which point is actually
selected there. So, it's right next to
this little spot, and you can see there
is this spot in the ceramic there, okay?
And as I uh
if I was to select everything with A,
and then if I was to hit uh to rotate,
you can see that the texture is being
updated over there. In fact, if I turn
off the overlay there just to uh see it
more clearly, and then I turn on the
thickness, right?
Watch this. As I select everything in
edit mode, I can move this around, and
the texture coordinates are updating in
real time. Okay, I can also scale this
by hitting S, and this is a really
common thing you do, because like often
a mesh is a completely different size to
the captured size of the object. Um in
Polygon's case, for like detailed
textures like this, this is a 30 by 30
cm texture, which is actually probably
pretty perfect for a plate. Maybe a
maybe a plate should be a little bit uh
scaled in like that, so that the dots
are a little bit bigger. But, you could
see this is very, very easy to do. Let's
go back to layout over here. I'm going
to select the icing now, and let's do uh
one that's a little bit more
complicated. So, I'm going to hit N to
bring up the properties again. I'm going
to scroll down, so this is in the
textures free category. Scrolling down,
and I'm looking for the strawberry pink
uh glaze. Okay, so we got this
strawberry pink um texture, right? And
this was actually captured um by
literally pouring a bunch of icing into
a pan, um and then using a stereoscopic
scanner to capture it from all
dimensions, so that you get this like
really interesting like that height
information there, the little bumps of
like the sugar crystals and stuff
popping through. Pretty cool. Anyways,
let's hit apply on that.
Okay, you could see there is some
texture on here, unlike the plate which
came in like nothing. And the reason for
that is that when you add in um a torus,
like certain primitives, we added in a
torus, it actually comes in with UV
unwrapping already created, okay? So,
with this this one here.
So, it's already got some UVs, but all
that extra work that we did at the
bottom there, like extruding some things
down, that's all been missed, all of the
way that things have been shifted,
because now it's lumpy, all of that is
missing as well. So, it would help to
actually UV unwrap this again, and
project these points in a way that
actually match matches the mesh. So, the
way to think about this is what if this
mesh was made of paper, and we had to
lay the paper flat over onto this
texture on the left-hand side over here?
Where would you place the cuts on the
mesh in order to lay it flat? And in the
case of something like this, where I
would place the cuts would be
essentially along the edge, right along
here. Okay, so if I alt click along that
edge there, that should select all the
way around it. So, do check that it goes
all the way around it. Um if it doesn't,
then it just this next step will come
out a little bit funny. Um anyways, now
that I've selected that, to add a cut,
we're going to hit control E,
and then I'm going to select mark seam,
okay? And now, if I was to go back into
uh wireframe mode here, and then just
turn off the selection, you should see
that we've got a line here that is red.
By the way, the one next to it that is
purple, that is the one that has the
crease, which we added when we used the
solidify thing to make it cling to the
uh to the donut a little bit better. So,
we've got this line that goes all the
way around it, okay? And that has done a
cut. Now, nothing has changed yet,
because we still haven't UV unwrapped
it, and that's okay, because we need to
do one more
right in the middle of our donut. If you
just select like a random point on the
inside of the donut there, then hit your
focus key, um tilde three or numpad
period,
then you should be able to get in nice
and close to it. Now that I'm here, I'm
going to do the same thing, so hold down
alt, and then select this line here, and
now I'm going to hit control E, and do
another seam. Okay, now that I've done
that, select the entire mesh, and just
like before, to unwrap it, it's U, U to
unwrap, and unwrap angle based. Now,
watch what happens.
Ready?
Well, that's taking a long time. I don't
know why it took that long. [laughter]
I've never seen it stall like that
before, okay? Anyways, but look,
that is perfect. That's pretty well
perfect. I mean, there's probably a
little bit of stretching there. There's
always going to be stretching, guys.
You'll never get it perfect, but as long
as the stretching is minimal, like that
is pretty well good. It's laid flat,
like it looks almost like a cowhide rug,
you know, like the and the dead animal
that's been stretched out. It looks like
that, but like that's that's how it
works, right? So, now if I go into
material view, look at this now.
We no longer have I mean, you couldn't
really see it clearly before, but you no
longer have the stretching um that was
happening there. It's now been properly
um
stretched across it. It's been properly
mapped, and so we've got the texture
going all the way in there. Now, the
scale of this is probably wrong. So, um
I like to like change the scale here,
and I want to see it over there. So, I
like to turn off my over uh overlays at
the top there. So, you can just click
that little box, that'll turn off
everything, so you kind of can see
what's selected, and now I can just
change the scale here,
um and I could make it bigger or
smaller, um
but yeah, you can play with the size,
and and try and get it good. But, why
does it look so pale and pink and like
not as fun as it was before? Well, it's
because when we added in that texture,
right? When we clicked this, it overrode
overrode um
the material that we had before. So, if
you go back to your shading tab, you'll
see we got all these textures, and for
example, before we had a pink color that
was in the base color. Now, it's been
overridden with the actual strawberry
color, which was captured with the
camera. However, that strawberry is a
little paler than what I want. So, I'm
actually going to disconnect it, because
there's not actually that much
information in color when it's something
like this. All the information is in the
bump. So, we can really just get by with
Actually, we don't need metallic, cuz
there's definitely no metal in it. Um
I'm going to keep the roughness. That's
okay to keep, because I just actually
want to see that. I'm going to
disconnect this, which is the subsurface
amount, um because I want to control
that myself as well. And I'm just going
to leave the roughness and the normal,
and that's it. Oh, I should explain how
I was disconnecting those. So, if you
hold down control and then right-click
drag, that is how you can disconnect.
You can also just click these points,
and then just disconnect like that, but
I prefer to control right-click drag,
and that'll cut it. Um sever the tie.
And now that I'm here, I'm just going to
set these values to what I had before,
you know, just playing it by eye, what
pink color looks good. Set my subsurface
amount radius to one, and then I'll
change this uh scale value till it looks
nice. But, there you go. I've now got my
fleshy pink donut,
um
but I I now have this lovely bubbly um
sugar crystals real glaze going on the
donut.
All right, now let's do another fun one.
Let's do the donut itself. Now, this is
a an interesting one that I had my team
do um before we did
uh before I started recording. Um I had
them go out and scan a real donut, scan
it all the way around, and then map it
to a torus, and then just get the
extracted data. And because this has
been already UV unwrapped to map the
exact square, just like what we um uh
sorry.
Yeah, just like what is captured for
this this type of map here, now I can
just apply this, and it'll automatically
do it. So, let's do that. Hit apply, and
that's pretty good. Like that's nice
color, we've got nice bump there. If we
bring back our icing, you can see that's
already pretty good, right? But, there
is something else that we can do,
because when I was talking about
shading, you might remember I mentioned
that there is two different ways of um
uh creating normal I sorry, creating
bumps, right? And the the the normal
one, the purple one, that's the one
we've been using uh thus far. But,
there's another one here, which comes in
disconnected, and it's the displacement
map. Now, in the newer versions of um
the Polygon add-on, like the next
version that's coming out after this,
you'll be able to in this last use box
here, you'll have an option that says um
displacement and I sorry, displacement
type. You can currently see it in
Cycles, so if you use that, you can
change it here to displacement and bump.
But, because Eevee only just came with
this feature to enable displacement,
it's not yet there.
Um so, we would have to connect it um
ourselves. But, essentially all it's
doing is when you change that little
drop down there, if I grab all these
things here, hit G to move them down,
and then I sever this tie with the
normal, and then I take my displacement,
don't put it in the normal input though,
put it in the displacement output of the
material here. And what this is doing
now
is well, it's it's still a fake bump,
but the other setting that it would
enable is here in your material
properties, right down here at the
bottom, where it says displacement, it
would change that to displacement and
bump. And now, if I select my icing, it
H to hide it, um you can see that the
mesh has changed, right? This is the
underlying mesh. It's now kind of
expanded. And this is actually the
captured data of the height, and it's
being projected out of the donut. But,
it can only use the actual data, which
is on the mesh, okay? So, it currently
looks kind of like chunky, um because
there's not enough information. So, if
you go to your modifier panel here, and
then what would we add to more add more
geometry? We would add in another
subdivision surface.
And now, when we do that, if I increase
this,
you can see if I increase it two, three,
four times in the viewport, you can see
I get a lot more data come through.
Okay, I I think three is about it. Um
I'm just going to I'll I'll set render
to three or four. Yeah, I'll set it to
three. That should be fine.
Um it comes in a little bit projected.
If you want to change the scale of it,
you can also do that
um here. I could change the scale from
.2 to about .15.
Also, you should see how it looks with
your icing. So, I'm going to hit Alt H.
Um you can see it's actually, yeah,
clipping through it. So, I'll select my
donut again, and I'll change the scale
here to about
.12.
Like that. And then, of course, the
other value that this is missing is the
subsurface scattering, because again, we
overrode the the placeholder stuff that
we had there before. So, in here, I'm
going to sever this connection, and then
I'm going to set this to one, and then
I'll just make this, you know, whatever.
And look, you can make this look like so
buttery nice. Like look at how soft and
fluffy this donut looks.
How cool is that?
Like that.
Bring it back. Look at that. We've got
real icing with the real crystals. We've
got real donut that has been captured
and projected onto our torus.
Um and that's just two materials, which
is really cool. The final object to
texture is our mug, and I'm going to do
that in the next part, because we need
to go much deeper into UV unwrapping and
show how to unwrap a custom object. So,
join me in the next video.